Hey, you. Wanna team up
with a dependable front liner?
Are you sure you're strong?
A Fang of Smoldering
Insanity skillbook.
Fang of
Smoldering Insanity
Skillbook
Skillbooks are items required
to unlock skill trees.
They're rare,
so I won't find one right away,
but looking for one is free.
Remaining skill points: 5
Oath of the Heavy Armor
Defense Booster
Beginner Swordsmanship
Oath of the Heavy Armor
and Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
These two skill trees work together
to complete the Heavy Knight.
The completed Heavy Knight
is no longer a defense specialist.
Even calling it an offensive specialist
isn't right either.
It's a human weapon.
Fang of Smoldering Insanity is essential
to unlocking the Heavy Knight's potential.
Loading
Begin Adventure
Episode 5
Fang of Smoldering
Insanity
Whoa, she's cute...
but out of my league.
Don't waste it.
I know. Thanks, Dad.
A Fang of Smoldering Insanity skillbook
is a key item for the Heavy Knight.
It'd be great if I could find one
in this city.
Excuse me.
Could I get three healing potions?
Sure thing. That'll be 72,000 gold.
That's a lot more
expensive than in the game.
That said, there's no way around it.
Fine.
By the way, I have a question.
Where can I buy skillbooks?
Oh...
I couldn't find any at any shops.
A Heavy Knight is stuck
in tutorial mode until
Yah!
Croak
Skree
they find a Fang of
Smoldering Insanity skillbook.
I have to get my hands on one.
Yes!
You don't know anything, do you?
Huh?
Are you a first-year adventurer
who just got his class?
Y-Yeah.
Buying and selling
skillbooks is prohibited.
What?
People are permitted
to use skillbooks they acquire,
but otherwise, the Adventurer's Guild
gives them to nobles and the church.
Y-You're kidding, right?!
Skillbooks are an unbelievably rare drop.
It's assumed you'll have to buy them.
You can't expect to find the one you want.
I did feel that nobles were more powerful
than they were in the game, but...
I can't believe this is happening.
It's likely that my family, the Edvaughns,
have all the skillbooks
collected in Rondalm.
Oh, fine.
I'm not supposed to tell you this,
but I'll make an exception.
You know, since you bought
the healing potions.
Here. Go to this place.
What's this?
A shop that deals in scavenged goods.
Scavengers. Are those people
who loot dead adventurers?
Aren't those items supposed to be
reported to the Adventurer's Guild?
They have an unspoken agreement.
The guild knows about these
underground shops and leaves them be.
Some adventurers can't
survive without scavenging.
Besides, even if they followed
standard procedure,
most items would end up in the hands of
nobles instead of their surviving family.
Nobles buy up skillbooks for cheap
and hoard them instead of using them.
They don't know how hard
it is to be an adventurer.
I was utterly naive.
If my memories
of my past life hadn't returned,
and I'd become a Master Swordsman...
Don't tell the mucky-mucks
about this shop.
Of course.
I'd rather die than tell anyone
I'm a noble's son.
We're partners now!
Do they really have skillbooks here?
They do. Five, even.
That's some dinky armor.
This Hall of Broken Grimoires
isn't for newbies like you.
I have gold. Could I see your Skillbooks?
You're welcome to look.
Your filthy fingerprints won't
make them any less valuable.
Thanks.
Beginner Archery Skillbook.
Beginner Archery
Market Price: 2,000,000G
Market price: two million gold.
Two million gold?!
That's 500,000 gold more
expensive than the game!
In the game, the market price was based
on trades made between players.
This price is probably based
on actual trade prices, too.
The price of skillbooks must be inflated
due to nobles hoarding them.
Just so you know, I'd charge
three million gold for that.
Th-Three million?!
Of course. This is a risky
business I'm running.
The officials look the other way,
but if their superiors find out,
I could lose my head.
Basic beginner skillbooks
are this expensive...
Even if I sell the Daemonsrage Shield,
I'll only have three million gold.
Current Funds: Approx. 900,000G
I doubt that's enough
to buy a rare skillbook.
Beginner Archery, Magic Booster,
Jack-in-the-Box, and Elemental Guard.
They're pretty rare, but they're
not what I'm looking for.
What's this last one?
This is it!
The skill tree essential to Heavy Knight,
Fang of Smoldering Insanity!
Once I have this, I'm golden!
What's this? You look awfully happy.
You must be an oddball if you want that.
Ma'am, this book...
I'd charge fifty million gold for that.
Fifty...
I'm amazed you keep such expensive
merchandise out without any guards.
If you think I'm weak, try me.
I threw five guys out on
their asses the other day.
Could you hold onto this skillbook for me?
I promise I'll come back
with fifty million gold.
What's in it for me?
What? Well, uh...
I don't dislike kids like you.
Huh?
Sure. I'll hold onto it.
Really?
Sure.
For an extra five million gold.
She drives a hard bargain.
I'll be finding ways
to make money for a while.
How'd it go with them?
I'd like to team up again.
I put my own spin on it.
That is so cute.
Fifty-five million gold, huh?
That's sixty times what I made
from that raid quest.
High-level adventurers
and the shops they deal with
have a busted perspective of wealth.
Fang of Smoldering Insanity
is a rare skill tree,
but the only ones who want it are
Heavy Knights and combat junkies
with a death wish.
More obviously powerful skillbooks
must be absurdly expensive.
I have to come up with practical
ways to make money.
I could try to get rich quick
by farming rare drops in dungeons.
All right!
No, Heavy Knights don't have skills
to deal consistent damage.
Roar
Aaah
Impossible
I could farm weak monsters
with Rampart Reflection.
Hmph!!
Croak
Hmph
That would take too long.
Impossible
Attack Skills
Beginner
Swordsmanship
I could use Beginner Swordsmanship
Beginner
Swordsmanship
or find another Skillbook
and build up those skill trees.
Attack Skills
Beginner
Swordsmanship
Attack Skills
Beginner
Swordsmanship
No, I'd stop using them once I acquired
Fang of Smoldering Insanity.
Attack Skills
Beginner
Swordsmanship
I'd like to avoid wasting skill points.
Attack Skills
Beginner
Swordsmanship
Impossible
He's a veteran adventurer,
and I was so rude to him.
Again?!
Heavy Knights aren't popular,
but that raid quest should've
gotten my name out there.
I'd have a lot more options
if I teamed up with other adventurers.
Allies...
I-I'll keep it busy while you run.
You doubt Elymas?
Then you're insulting me
for approving his promotion!
I guess I'll find allies.
Man, I wasn't expecting
a Blood-Soaked Sword to drop.
The market price is two million gold.
We can have fun with that for a while.
It's because of my skills, you know.
Silence...
What?
They worked, didn't they?
A Swordsman, a Bandit, and a Pierrot?
Because of you, huh?
We finally got this rare drop after
visiting the dungeon a bunch of times.
I'm not sure that it really was
because of your skills.
No, you're right.
B-But if we visit more dungeons,
you'll start to see the difference.
We're just getting started.
Don't tell me, Ruche...
You're so weak. Do you really think
you'll get a cut of the sale?
What?
But...
But I risk my life fighting
on the front line, too.
At least give me a fifth.
No, wait. 200,000...
A hundred thousand gold would be nice.
What?
Just kidding.
Listen, you may be risking your life,
but you don't have
any decent attack skills.
You just soak up some hits.
That's the problem.
You're not actually useful.
I-I don't have attack skills...
because I assigned my skill points
like you told me to.
What?
D-Don't you think it's mean to say that
once we've made a bunch of money?
Mean?
Mean, huh?
I think you're confused.
Reducing our take
when you're useless is a problem.
Besides, I just made a little suggestion.
You're the one who actually
assigned your skill points.
Now you're blaming me and demanding
a share when you've contributed nothing.
Mr. Cline?
A bad build and argument
over how to split the treasure.
That happened all the time
in Magic World, too.
This isn't what we agreed to!
That's your problem!
You assign your skill points
to fit your party,
but the situation changes,
and your choices become meaningless.
Fine, fine.
Here.
That's 100,000 gold.
This is what you wanted, right?
Pick it up and get out of here.
We kept you around even though you're
weak and don't have decent attack skills,
and now you're showing your true colors
because you're blinded by chump change.
Right, Reiss?
Don't you agree?
I guess so.
It's not like we can afford to share
the wealth we happened to acquire.
Th-That's not what I meant!
I'm sorry, Mr. Cline and Ms. Reiss!
I actually don't need
any gold for the sword!
Sorry doesn't cut it.
We just can't anymore.
Well, good luck with your next party.
Though I don't know who'd recruit a loser
who can't level up anymore
because of their bad build.
They say relationships only last
as long as the money does.
The skill point system is brutal.
You have to farm monsters at or above
your level to get any decent experience.
You don't have any decent attack skills.
You just soak up some hits.
That's the problem.
You're not actually useful.
But if your build is bad and you
struggle against enemies your level,
Nooo!
Croak!
raising your level becomes
incredibly difficult.
Croak!
Did she put her points in Speed Booster
or a weapon skill tree she doesn't need?
Since she's a Pierrot,
is it a support tree?
I wasn't expecting
a Blood-Soaked Sword to drop.
It's because of my skills, you know.
They worked, didn't they?
Because of you, huh?
We finally got this rare drop after
visiting the dungeon a bunch of times.
I'm not sure that it really was
because of your skills.
Could it be?
Does she have that skill tree?
Who'd kick someone with that skill tree?
But based on that conversation,
that must be it.
If I'm right, she's got
a broken skill tree.
I'm sorry for being selfish!
You never have to pay me again!
Please keep me in the party!
Wh-Who are you?!
Please!
Please! Will you form a party with me?
A p-p-party?!
Translator:
Sho Stifler
Timer:
Krzysztof Kunc
Editor:
Salem Alabanza
Quality Control:
Gabriella Alabanza
Final Quality Control:
Sriram Gurunathan
While looking for party members,
I reached out to a Pierrot girl.
Panic
Now that I think about it,
maybe that was sketchy of me.
But the guys who kicked her
from their party don't know anything.
They don't understand
the power hidden inside her.
Next time, "Ruche the Pierrot."
I need her.